valero.com 2013-03-31

# Privacy Statement

**  
**Valero Marketing and Supply Company and its affiliates (collectively “Valero”) have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and should be read in conjunction with the Legal Notice & Terms of Use. Due to the sensitive nature of the information we collect from our customers, which may include, your address, phone numbers and credit card information, we believe it is important to satisfy strict privacy requirements. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: www.valero.com (the “Site”) and how we handle information we learn about you from your visit to our Site. 

The information that we receive and use depends on what you do when you visit our Site. 

\--Privacy 

IP Address   
Cookies   
Consumer Information/Information Collection   
Other Nonpublic Personal Information   
Disclosure of Personal Information   
Advertising and Promotions   
Acceptance of Offers   
Prospect Information   
Web Site Links   
Privacy Policy Changes   
-Security   
-Supplementation Information   
-Children's Privacy   
-Choice/Opt-Out   
-Contacting the Web Site

**IP Address  
** When your web browser or e-mail application requests a web page or e-mail from another computer on the Internet, it automatically gives that computer the address where it should send the information. This is called your computer's "IP address." (IP stands for "Internet protocol.") For most users accessing the Internet from a dial-up Internet service provider (ISP), the IP address will be different every time you log on. We use your IP address to help diagnose service or technology problems with our server, and to administer our Site. We use your IP address to send you the most appropriate advertising based on geographic area or information derived from your IP address. Many IP addresses are commonly associated with Internet service providers, universities, or major corporations in specific regions or localities. Aggregate information derived from IP addresses may also be reported to advertisers. Your IP address is used to help identify you, to track activity within our Site and to gather broad demographic information which is used to further develop advertisements, products and services. 

**Cookies**   
A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Our Site uses cookies to keep track of your session ID. We may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests or to track specific data that needs to be available on multiple web pages. Cookies are necessary for the system to work properly. Any cookie in use by our web server is temporary and will be removed when the user logs out or is timed-out by the server. Our server contains links to other related web sites. We do not control or have access to the information that is collected or used on those sites, via cookie or otherwise. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use our products or services that require you to "sign in," and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings. 

**Consumer Information/Information Collection  
** When you browse the Site and have not registered for any online service from Valero, you browse anonymously. Personal information -- such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail address -- is not collected as you browse. Valero does, however, use 

"cookies" to collect non-personal information about how our Site is used. Non-personal information, such as the server your computer is logged onto, your browser type (for example, Netscape or Internet Explorer), and whether you responded to a Valero banner ad or e-mail is collected and tracked. This non-personal information is used for the purpose of measuring response rates to banner ads and e-mail offers. 

Registration for Online Products and Services. In order to provide you with a particular product or service online, we may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information, including your e-mail address and credit card account number (if you are a Diamond Shamrock, TOTAL, or Ultramar-Beacon credit cardholder, for example), for purposes such as correspondence, site registration, checking your bill online, making a purchase, or participating in online surveys and enabling us to provide an online product or service to you in an efficient manner.   
If you are known to us as a registered user of a Valero online service, we may combine information about your use of the Site and the online product or service you utilize with certain other online and offline information we have about you as a Valero customer and information you have provided to us as well as information available from external sources, such as census bureau data, in order to customize your online experience and present you with relevant online and offline offers and updates. We also use a "cookie" to enable our server to recognize you as a registered Valero online service user when you re-enter our Site. If you would like to learn more about cookies, please read about 

Cookies for more information. Your individually identifiable information is used to contact you when necessary, such as when we make changes to our Privacy and Security Policy or Legal Notice & Terms of Use. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings, or be deleted from our Site and customer information database; see the -Choice/Opt-Out section below. 

**Other Nonpublic Personal Information**  
When you submit your information for a credit card application, Valero retrieves a credit report. Valero may also generate and store a consumer credit score and personalized recommendations for each registered user. Some registered users may also receive pre-approved offers of credit while at the Site. Registered users may request Valero to retrieve and generate this credit-related information multiple times in a year at no cost to you. The credit report is typically stored for approximately 45 days. The scores, recommendations and any offers viewed or accepted and the dates of that information may be stored indefinitely. While these items are not sold to third parties for any reason, they may be used to qualify registered users for certain products, services or promotions. See the 

Disclosure of Personal Information section below for additional information. 

**Disclosure of Personal Information  
** From time to time, we enter into contractual agreements with nonaffiliated, third party providers, such as marketers, Web hosting facilities, transaction processors and decisioning systems. In the course of providing services, these parties may receive your personally identifiable information. These parties, however, are obligated by contract to maintain the confidentiality of the information. 

We use the demographic information in your profile to tailor your experience at our Site, showing the users content that we think they might be interested in, and displaying the content according to their preferences. 

**Advertising and Promotions**  
While at our Site, we may use information you provide to inform you of products and services offered by Valero and third parties, as well as advertisements and promotions for products and services offered at other web sites or retail establishments. If you click on an ad or promotion which appears on our site without accepting an offer for a product or service, we will not provide individually identifiable data to the third party offering the ad or promotion. Overall demographic information may be shared with these advertisers on an aggregate basis, without individually identifiable information. 

**Acceptance of Offers**   
If you accept products or services offered by third parties while remaining on our Site, individually identifiable information required for such acceptance, such as name, address and social security number, provided to us will be transmitted to the third party only upon final acceptance of that product or service. Customers will be informed that they are accepting a product or service of a third party, and may or may not be subsequently linked to the third party's web site. Third party suppliers might include providers of financial services, credit information, or other consumer products, and may have privacy policies related to their web site, the internet and e-commerce which are different than ours. If you do not want your individually identifiable information shared with any third parties, do not accept any offers for services from third party organizations. Prior to any such acceptance you will be informed that some or all of your individually identifiable and nonpublic information may likely be shared with that organization. 

Valero may make other disclosures as permitted or required by law to nonaffiliated third parties in addition to those described in the notice. 

**Prospect Information  
** Our Site encourages registered users to send e-mail messages to us and to provide us with e-mail and name information for friends who may be interested in the services and information provided at our Site. We provide the registered user with an e-mail hyperlink to refer friends to our Site. That information is stored in a prospect database and is listed as a referral from the registered user for up to 90 days. This information is not sold or distributed to any third parties. 

**Web Site Links**   
This Site contains links to other sites. Valero is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. Please refer to those sites for specific information about their privacy or security practices or policies. 

**Changes to the Privacy and Security Policy**   
The protection of consumer information is one the guiding principles behind Valero. Because of that stance, registered users will be notified via e-mail (if you have provided us with your e-mail address) of any changes to the 

Privacy and Security Policy. We will also post a change notification marker on www.valero.com home page for review. 

**Security**  
This Site has security measures in place to protect against the negligent or inadvertent loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Valero’s networking systems include an industry standard firewall and systems that are both physically and logically protected (via secured locations and passwords). Consumer information will be regularly backed-up and stored in a secure location. Credit Report information will be kept on our servers in encrypted format for a maximum of 45 days. Other consumer data (such as name, address, etc.) will be kept on an industry standard computer database fully protected behind a firewall. 

If you have specific additional questions about Valero’s systems or the storage of data, please contact us online 

[Customer.Relations@valero.com. ](mailto:Customer.Relations@valero.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy)**Supplementation Information**   
This Site supplements the information you provide us with information that is received from third parties, such as credit bureaus and census data. 

**Children's Privacy**   
Our Commitment to Children's Privacy: Protecting the privacy of children is especially important. For this reason, we never collect or maintain information at our Site from those we actually know are under 18, and no part of our Site is structured to attract anyone under 18. 

**Choice/Opt-Out**   
Our Site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from affiliates or non-affiliated third parties at the point where we request information about the visitor. The benefits of remaining on our mailing list include e-mail notification about enhanced service or product offerings that we believe may be of interest to you. This Site gives registered users the following option for removing their information from our e-mail database to not receive future offers and communications via e-mail, direct mail or telemarketing. You can send e-mail to 

[Customer.Relations@valero.com](mailto:Customer.Relations@valero.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy). 

**Safe Harbor Certification  
** With respect to the personal data it receives from countries European Union, Valero has certified its adherence to the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles.  You can find Valero's Safe Harbor certification at [](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)<https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx> .  For more information about these Safe Harbor Principles, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's website at [](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)

[http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/). 

**Contacting the Web Site**   
If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can contact: 

[Customer.Relations@valero.com](mailto:Customer.Relations@valero.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy). 

All trademarks depicted are the intellectual property of their respective owners. Please see our 

Legal Notice & Terms of Use for more information or contact us at [Customer.Relations@valero.com](mailto:Customer.Relations@valero.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy).
